MOQU - Discovery

Our Mission:

MOQU (木) generally translates to "wood" in Japanese. For us, the word also stands for MOdern design + QUality. As furniture designers, we believe that we should construct high quality and timeless products that last a lifetime, not only in physical form but also in terms of design, function and aesthetics. With our innovative design and process, we

create modular furniture for the discerning eye.

Our Products:

MOQU products are designed in Los Angeles and made in th e mountains of Hida, Japan, where the woodcraft heritage has existed for over 1,300 years. For generations, these Japanese craftsmen have found innovative uses for comple joineries called Arizan (ありざん)

in architecture, furniture and home goods. Building upon t his craftsmanship, MOQU has developed new forms of complex joineries that push the Arizan technique to the next level.

The namesake line shares the same philosophy of the Hi da region in conservationism. Sourced only from planted and second-growth forests with trees that have lived to abo ut 100 years, MOQU

s goal is to design each piece to last as many years as the trees that the material was derived from

http://architizer.com/blog/japanese-art-of-wood-joinery/

Satoshi Sakanoue

Education:

1996 - 1999

Art Center College of Design / Majored in Product design

Work experience:

2000 - 2001

Product + Graphic Designer

AZ works, Tokyo Japan

2001 - 2004

Freelance Designer

2004 - 2012

Product + Graphic Designer / CEO

Plus Alpha Co., Ltd. (Established)

2005 - 2012

Instructor of Product design

Tokyo Metropolitan Industrial Technology Research Institute, Tokyo Japan

2013 – Present

Freelance Designer

John Kim

https://prologuedesign.carbonmade.com/

*please also check resume

Quotes of design inspirations and influences

- 1. We were inspired by mid-century design and architecture when designing our modular furniture collection.
- 2. The collection is specifically influenced by the innovative work of Louis Kahn for Salk Institute in 1965.
- 3. MOQU design is the marriage of Japanese precision and American modern design.

John Kim Industrial Designer Education+ Art Center College of Design Pasadena 1996-1999 BS in Transportation Design

University of California, San Diego San Diego 1992-1995

BS in Bioengineering

Professional Experiences+

Boom Aerospace Consultant / Englewood, CO (2016 July – Current)

Currently developing the corporate lobby and visitor experience center for the aviation start-up, which plans to bring back supersonic air travel for the rst and business class travelers. The space inculdes interactive wall, -ight simulation, conference room, merchandize area, cafe, and information

desk to bring back the glamor of the golden age of -ying from the 60's.

Icon Aircraft Designer / Vacaville, CA (2015 Jan – 2016 June)

Created the enclosed tranporter for the A5 aircraft in time for the 2015 Osh Kosh Air Show in Wisconsin, using custom extruded space frames and coposite sandwich construction for the load-bearing walls. The project established new construction methods and design language that will in-uence the future RVs and trailers in otherwise staid industry.

IronGatsby Motorcycles Partner / Huntington Beach, CA (2011-2014)

Developed a line of custom, limited-run chopper motorcycles using S&S V-Twin crate engine. Focused on producing mostly custom components through 3D modeling, CNC milling, and 3D printing, an industry rst for the custom chopper community. Also introduced industrial design process and legimacy to chopper building as demonstrated through t and nish, quality, and robustness.

Votex Motors Lead Designer / Seattle, WA (2009-2011)

Vortex F-1 track car was the result of two years of development with the group of dedicated engineers, designers, and technicians who put together fully track-ready prototype in time for 2011 SEMA show in Las Vegas. The F-1 featured modular space frame, mid ship layout, turbocharged

GM Ecotech engine producing over 350 hp, and modied Ford Focus front and rear suspension. Hancook Tire graciously provided space for the F-1 to be displayed along side the famed Rys Millen's Hyundai Genesis Formula D drift car.

Photo Center Inc. Partner / Costa Mesa, CA (2007 – 2009)

Joined forces with my father to run the family-owned prinitng business. While initally catering mostly to professional photographers and graphic designers, I refocused the direction of the business to corporate clients such as Mattel, Volcom, Hurley, Mitsubishi, and other companies based in LA. We provided printing collaterals for in-house presentations, marketing materials, and special events.

Ford Motor Company Senior Designer / Dearborn, MI (1998 – 2006)

Developed important segment-leading cars, SUVs, and trucks for the company such as the Taurus, Explorer, Expedition, F-150, F-250, and Flex. Show cars included Explorer Sportsman and

Bronco. In addition to leading the design process, I participated in market research, consumer clinic, clay modeling, wind tunnel testing, track shake-down, and safety crash. Daily work encompassed meetings and presenting to upper management for product planning, product cycle, facelifts, trim levels, options, and varients. Also managed various vendors responsible for each components, working closely with studio engineers.

Freelance+ Los Angeles, CA (2005- Current)

Past and on-going freelance projects include designing street shoes, bags, and accessories for Puma, Creative Recreations, Evolv, and KimKim Artifacts. Most recent work consists of collection

of modular furniture for Moqu of Japan.

Academic+

Hancock University Adjunct Professor / Long Beach, CA (2012-2014)

Developed project-based curriculcum for Junior/Senior industrial design students Invited and established network with designers from VW, Calty, and GM based in Los Angeles. Emphasized concept and story, presentation skills, 3D and physical modeling to support their projects.

College for Creative Studies Adjunct Professor / Detroit, MI (2003-2005)

Taught fundamental design classes in Product, Transportation, and Visual Communication for Freshmen and Sophomore students. Worked closely with newly elected Trans dept chair Brian Fitzpatrick to develop and implement core curriculum and bring new professors on board. Skills+

- Concept development, Ideation sketches, rendering, 3D modeling, surface review, prototyping, prodcution feasibility
- Market research, demographic study, brand strategy, product planning, consumer clinic
- Software: Photoshop, Illustrator, Autodesk Alias, Keyshot, Powepoint
- Language: Fluent in English and Korean